Chetan Lodha

8638722737 | chetan.lodha23@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/chetanlodha23 | github.com/chetanlodha

Summary

A dedicated Software Engineer with demonstrated experience in full-stack development through multiple projects involving REST API integration, microservices architecture and CI/CD. Adept at working within Agile environments and managing tasks efficiently to meet project deadlines while maintaining the highest standards.

EDUCATION

Teerthanker Mahaveer University

August 2017 - June 2021

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering

CPI - 80.24

EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services

Full Time

Systems Engineer

December 2021 - Present

Assistant Systems Engineer - Trainee

July 2021 - November 2021

- Migrated deployment of AWS Resources to Terraform, resulting in 20% faster deployments and near 0 unexpected failures
- Developed and maintained 10+ AWS Lambda Functions written in Python.
- Built, deployed and managed MuleSoft REST APIs (10+), applications (20+), custom component and custom policies (5+).
- Created integration test suite for 40+ MuleSoft Applications and 10+ Lambda Functions.
- Created 5+ utilities for intensive tasks such as Swagger creation and Token generation, resulting in **reduced effort** and time required by up to 90%.
- Planned and executed the roll-out of an upgraded MuleSoft Runtime across 10+ environments. Received appreciation for incident free delivery in a short time-span of 4 weeks.
- Led and collaborated across teams during critical incidents such as to restore unplanned environment outages on 10+ occasions

FindMind Analytics Pvt. Ltd.

Internship

Front-end Intern

June 2020 - August 2020

- Built 10+ new features into their portal integrate charts, pop-over actions, email templates, etc
- Re-implemented 3+ pages following updated design
- Debugged and fixed issues in existing features and code base

Projects

 ${\bf Sharehere} \mid {\bf Front\text{-}end\text{-} JavaScript,\, jQuery,\, Bootstrap,\, HTML,\, CSS,\, Node.js}$

November 2020 - August 2021

- Responsible for creating **responsive and highly performant** front-end and notification delivery system of this project
- Custom implementation for a Single Page Application like experience
- Micro-interactions and animated components using vanilla CSS
- Event driven real time notification and messages delivery using Socket.io and Node.js

Quick Notes | Full-stack - Mongo.db, Express.js, React.js, Node.js

August 2020 - July 2021

- Smooth animations using CSS spread throughout the interface for most actions and interactions
- JWT based sessions for authentication
- CRUD operations for notes using Express.js and Mongo.db as the database provider

Additional Information

Skills: Terraform, Python, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, HTML, CSS, Core JAVA, Mongo.db, SQL, Git,

Docker

Cloud Platforms: AWS, MuleSoft

Awards: Service & Commitment Award, Elevate Wings Award, On The Spot Award

Certifications: MuleSoft Certified Developer - Level 1 (Mule 4)